# **Arpita Mangal**

(628)488-2112 ♦ amangal@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ LinkedIn ♦ Github ♦ Portfolio

#### PROFILE

Data Science professional with 3+ years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing data-driven solutions. Experienced in customer segmentation, journey enhancement, & competitor analytics, driven by problem-solving mindset. **Specialities:** Experimental Design, Causal Inference, Exploratory Analysis, Visualization, Supervised & Unsupervised Learning **Libraries:** Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, PySpark, Keras, TensorFlow, Pyomo, Cvxpy, NLTK, Genism, SapCy

Technologies: Python, SQL, R, Tableau, Advanced Excel, Confluence, Jira, Git Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of California, Davis**

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics (GPA 3.67/4.0)

Expected Jun. 2023

Highlighted Coursework: Statistics, Machine Learning, Logistics and Supply Chain, Data Scraping, Big Data, Time Series

## **Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur**

Kharagpur, IND

Dual Degree (BTech & MTech), Ocean Engineering and Naval Architecture

Jun. 2019

Highlighted Coursework: Recommender Systems, Data Analytics, Foundations of Entrepreneurship, Data Structures

#### PRACTICUM EXPERIENCE

#### **UC Davis Practicum Project, Qualcomm**

San Francisco (Remote)

Data Scientist, Practicum Project

Sep. 2023 - Present

Identifying user needs and preferences in the mobile device markets to improve branding & provide actionable business insights.

- Scrubbed 20K tweets containing Qualcomm references in mobile market & performed sentiment analysis using word2vec.
- Scraped features, ratings and reviews of 2500+ mobile devices from Amazon to interpret brand position & user preferences.
- Designed & conducted user surveys that evaluate 2K university students' current and future needs as mobile device owners.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Kotak Securities Limited Mumbai, IND

Data Scientist - Associate Vice President, Analytics & Strategy Team

Jul. 2021 - Jul. 2022

Improved customer acquisition, activation, and retention, increasing Customer Lifetime Value from INR 9K to INR 13.5K.

- Built a propensity data model & deep learning-based customer segmentation model to increase customer engagement.
- Optimized ad spend by targeting high-value customer, through focused marketing strategy saving 30% on acquisition cost.
- Single-handedly **coordinated** with multiple teams and stacked up their perspectives for understanding customer behaviour. Further, analysed and executed a pilot to increase **customer activation**, resulting in revenue growth in just two months.
- Utilized CRM data to enhance customer journey and identified account closure trends, resulting in a 5% boost in retention.

Barclays Global Services Pune, IND

Graduate Analyst (Developer)

Jul. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Developed features for mobile banking app as well as build a fraud detection model reducing average detection time by ~34%.

- Coded new app features while maintaining legacy code & prioritizing accessibility enhancements. Codebase: ~ 20000 lines.
- Classified personas to distinguish money mules from legitimate customers and suggested prevention & remediation plans.

# **PROJECTS**

# Warehouse Inventory Management, Optimization | Ongoing

Related Skills: Linear Programming, Network Flow, Forecast Supply & Demand, Time Series, Autocorrelation, Moving averages

# Estimate Price & Substitute of Medicines and Pharmaceutical Devices | Project Link

Related Skills: Predictive Analytics, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Text Analytics, Doc2Vec, Web Scraping, Market Research

# Recommend Events in an event-based Social Network | Project Link

Related Skills: Collaborative Filtering, Hybrid Recommender, Cold-Start Problem, TF-IDF, K-means Clustering, Feature Engineering

# Filling in Missing Values of Sea Surface Temperature | Project Link

Related Skills: Dealt with Spatio-Temporal Dataset, Non-Negative Matrix Factorization, Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)

### ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Awards: MSBA Fellowship, GSM Grant, 1st Position - Barclays Hackathon, Finalist -The Economist, Young Blood – GYWS

**Internships:** Cambridge Judge Business School, Kotak Securities Limited, REDX Innovation Lab, Flytxt **Leadership:** Public Relations Officer - GYWS (NGO), Governor - TAdS (Adventure Club, IIT Kharagpur)